### Clara Nelson

607-342-7906 | claran@alumni.cmu.edu | claranelson.github.io

#### SUMMARY

Senior software engineer specializing in the front end with full-stack experience. Product focused mindset experienced in weighing trade-offs across engineering and business considerations. Independently motivated to provide quality experiences for users and developers through bug fixes, team rituals, and mentoring junior engineers. Academic training in data structures and algorithms using C from Carnegie Mellon University.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Ordergroove Senior Software Engineer, Merchant Growth Team

December 2022 - present

Full stack, Front end focus

- Contributed to development standard and created components for new design system
- Independently learned Go and release processes to push time-critical tickets to production
- Investigated and scoped ADA compliance issues for WCAG Level AA using WAVE and Axe Devtools
- Resolved or triangulated urgent merchant and internal tickets requiring engineer input
- Designed and presented technical architecture training to internal team about Shopify and cart offers

## $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Ordergroove} Software Engineer, Merchant Growth Team \\ \end{tabular}$

July 2022 - December 2022

Front end

- Implemented re-branding of merchant portal serving DTC merchants ranging from SMB to Enterprise
- Planned redesign of subscription management interface to support internal plugins
- Implemented productized cart offers for Shopify based on learnings from prior proof of concept

## Ordergroove Software Engineer, Partnerships Team

August 2021 - July 2022

Back end

- Leveraged new Shopify webhook and API features to create webhooks for Ordergroove
- Implemented proof of concept of cart offers on Shopify

#### ARUP Full Stack Developer

April 2021 – August 2021

- Independently maintained and added features to Python automation handling time-sensitive documents
- Scoped, estimated, and completed new Python automation projects for internal clients

#### **ARUP** Advanced Technology and Research Graduate Analyst

July 2019 - March 2021

- Created relational database and interfaced with MongoDB to create Power BI dashboards
- Decreased runtime of existing data processing tool by about 5000x

### **EDUCATION**

#### Carnegie Mellon University Master of Science in Civil Engineering

May 2019

Focus Area: Advanced Infrastructure Systems

GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms (course 15-122), Data Mining and Machine Learning for Smart Structures, Data Analytics

#### Carnegie Mellon University Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

May 2018

GPA: 3.92

Minor: Philosophy

Relevant Coursework: Principles of Computing, Data Acquisition, Data Management, Python Prototyping and Web Development for Infrastructure, Building Controls and Diagnostics

#### SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python, Go, C

Frameworks/Tools: React, Redux, Node.js, Liquid, SASS, Django, Jest, Terraform